<resources>
    <string name="app_name">FooDish</string>
    <string name="welcome_to_foodish">Welcome to FooDish!</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="first_name">First Name</string>
    <string name="last_name">Last Name</string>
    <string name="type_your_email">Type your Email</string>
    <string name="home" />
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <string name="open_drawer">Open Drawer</string>
    <string name="close_drawer">Close Drawer</string>
    <string name="todoa">TODO</string>

    <string name="to">To</string>
    <string name="convert">Convert</string>
    <string name="from">From</string>
    <string name="enter_the_amount">Amount</string>
    <string name="unit_converter">Unit Converter</string>
    <string name="result">Result</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bottom2">Bottom2</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="foodish_description">FooDish is a Filipino food recipe application that provide users with a wide range of recipes typically for breakfast,lunch, and dinner meals. A list of recipes and food-related images make up the application that aims to simplify and help user enhance their cooking experience by providing a diverse array of recipe along with helpful features to help improve their cooking skills.</string>
    <string name="foodish_title">About FooDish</string>
    <string name="our_team">Our Team</string>
    <string name="james">Menard James Sayson\nBachelor of Information and Technology Programming\nsmenardjames@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="mharvin">Mharvin Caramat\nBachelor of Information and Technology Programming\ncaramatmharvin@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="aljon">Aljon Gutierrez\nBachelor of Information and Technology Programming\naljongutierrez08@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="julius">Julius Adrian Ramos\nBachelor of Information and Technology Programming\njuliuscervantesramos@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="alexander">John Alexander Vargas\nBachelor of Information and Technology Programming\njobe.vargas.up@phinmaed.com</string>
    <string name="foodish_mission">Our mission is to make Filipino culinary heritage accessible and enjoyable. We offer a diverse range of recipes, food imagery, and a user-friendly platform to promote a passion for cooking and culinary creativity.</string>
    <string name="foodish_vision">Our vision is to be the top choice for all seeking Filipino culinary exploration. We aim to evolve our app into a community for passionate home cooks and food enthusiasts. We envision FooDish as a symbol of culinary inspiration, offering a wide range of recipes and innovative features for users from all backgrounds.</string>
    <string name="mission">Mission</string>
    <string name="vision">Vision</string>
    <string name="pork_adobo">Pork Adobo</string>
    <string name="top_picks">Top picks</string>
    <string name="tinola">Tinola</string>
    <string name="menudo">Menudo</string>
    <string name="sinigang">Sinigang</string>
    <string name="pork_sisig">Pork Sisig</string>
    <string name="category">Category</string>
    <string name="adobos">Adobos</string>
    <string name="sinigangs">Sinigangs</string>
    <string name="sisigs">Sisigs</string>
    <string name="foodish_budget_tracker">Foodish Budget Tracker</string>
    <string name="enter_expense_name">Enter Expense Name</string>
    <string name="total_expense_php">Total Expense: PHP%1$s</string>
    <string name="enter_expense_amount_php">Enter Expense Amount(PHP)</string>
    <string name="add_expense">Add Expense</string>
    <string name="total_expense_php0_00">Total Expense: PHP0.00</string>
    <string name="bl_adobosagata">
         \u2022 3 pounds pork shoulder, cut into 2-inch cubes \n
         \u2022 1 onion, peeled and sliced thinly \n
         \u2022 1 head garlic, peeled and minced \n
         \u2022 ½ teaspoon peppercorns \n
         \u2022 2 bay leaves \n
         \u2022  1 cup water \n
         \u2022 ½ cup vinegar \n
         \u2022 ¼ cup soy sauce \n
         \u2022 1 tablespoon canola oil \n
         \u2022 1 cup coconut milk \n
         \u2022 2 Thai chili peppers, stemmed and chopped \n
         \u2022 Salt to taste \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_adobosagata">
        1.	In a pot over medium heat, combine pork, onions, garlic, peppercorns, bay leaves, water, vinegar and soy sauce. Bring to a boil for about 5 minutes, skimming scum that floats on top. \n
        2.	Lower heat, cover and simmer for about 30 to 40 minutes or until meat is tender. Drain meat. Reserve the aromatics and 1 cup of the liquid. \n
        3.	In a wide pan over medium heat, heat oil. Add meat and aromatics and cook, stirring occasionally, until lightly browned. \n
        4.	Add reserved liquid, coconut milk, and chili peppers. \n
        5.	Lower heat, cover and continue to cook for about 15 to 20 minutes or until meat is completely cooked and sauce is reduced and thickened. \n
        6.	Season with salt to taste.  Serve hot. \n \n
        Reference: https://www.kawalingpinoy.com/adobo-sa-gata/
    </string>
    <string name="instructions">Instructions:</string>
    <string name="ingredients">Ingredients:</string>
    <string name="adobo_sa_gata">Adobo sa Gata</string>
    <string name="sub_adobosagata">Cooking Time: 45 minutes (Good for 4-6 Persons)</string>
    <string name="batchoy_tagalog">Batchoy Tagalog</string>
    <string name="bl_batchoy_tagalog">
        \u2022 1 tablespoon canola oil \n
        \u2022 1 onion, peeled and sliced thinly \n
        \u2022 4 cloves garlic, peeled and minced \n
        \u2022 2 thumb-sized ginger, peeled and minced \n
        \u2022 ½ pound pork tenderloin, cut into strips \n
        \u2022 ¼ pound pork heart, about 1 piece, cut into thin strips \n
        \u2022 2 tablespoons fish sauce \n
        \u2022 6 cups water \n
        \u2022 ¼ pound pork liver, cut into thin strips \n
        \u2022 ¼ pound coagulated blood, drained and cut into cubes \n
        \u2022 salt and pepper to taste \n
        \u2022 2 ounces miswa \n
        \u2022 1 bunch fresh chili leaves, stems trimmed \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_batchoy_tagalog">
        1.	In a large pot over medium heat, heat oil. Add onions, garlic, and ginger, and cook until softened. \n
        2.	Add pork and heart. Cook, stirring occasionally, until lightly browned. \n
        3.	Add fish sauce and cook for about 2 to 3 minutes. \n
        4.	Add water and bring to a boil, skimming scum that floats on top. \n
        5.	Lower heat, cover, and continue to cook for about 15 to 20 minutes or until meat is tender. \n
        6.	Increase heat to high and bring the broth to a rolling boil. \n
        7.	Add pork liver and cook, without stirring, for about 2 to 3 minutes. Stir and continue to cook for another 2 to 3 minutes. \n
        8.	Add coagulated blood and cook, without stirring, for about 2 to 3 minutes. Stir and continue to cook for about 8 to 10 minutes. \n
        9.	Season with salt and pepper to taste. \n
        10.	Add miswa and continue to cook for 1 to 2 minutes. \n
        11.	Add chili leaves, pressing down into the broth. Turn off the heat and cover to allow residual steam to cook leaves. Serve hot. \n \n
        Reference: https://www.kawalingpinoy.com/batchoy-tagalog/
    </string>
    <string name="chicken_adobo">Chicken Adobo</string>
    <string name="bl_chicken_adobo">
        \u2022 2 lbs chicken \n
        \u2022 3 pieces dried bay leaves \n
        \u2022 6 tablespoons soy sauce \n
        \u2022 4 tablespoons white vinegar \n
        \u2022 5 cloves garlic \n
        \u2022 1 1/2 cups water \n
        \u2022 3 tablespoons cooking oil \n
        \u2022 1 teaspoon sugar \n
        \u2022 1/4 teaspoon salt \n
        \u2022 1 teaspoon whole peppercorn \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_chicken_adobo">
        1.	Combine chicken, soy sauce, and garlic in a large bowl. Mix well. Marinate the chicken for at least 1 hour. Note: the longer the time, the better \n
        2.	2 lbs chicken, 6 tablespoons soy sauce \n
        3.	Heat a cooking pot. Pour cooking oil. \n
        4.	3 tablespoons cooking oil \n
        5.	When the oil is hot enough, pan-fry the marinated chicken for 2 minutes per side. \n
        6.	Pour-in the remaining marinade, including garlic. Add water. Bring to a boil \n
        7.	1 1/2 cups water \n
        8.	Add dried bay leaves and whole peppercorn. Simmer for 30 minutes or until the chicken gets tender \n
        9.	3 pieces dried bay leaves, 1 teaspoon whole peppercorn \n
        10.	Add vinegar. Stir and cook for 10 minutes. \n
        11.	4 tablespoons white vinegar \n
        12.	Put-in the sugar, and salt. Stir and turn the heat off.Serve hot. Share and Enjoy! \n
        13.	1 teaspoon sugar, 1/4 teaspoon salt \n \n

        Reference: https://panlasangpinoy.com/filipino-chicken-adobo-recipe/#wprm-recipe-container-47216

    </string>
    <string name="sub_cook30_good24">Cooking time: 30 minutes (Good for 2-4 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook30_good46">Cooking time: 30 minutes (Good for 4-6 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook40_good24">Cooking time: 40 minutes (Good for 2-4 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook40_good46">Cooking time: 40 minutes (Good for 4-6 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook50_good24">Cooking time: 50 minutes (Good for 2-4 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook50_good46">Cooking time: 50 minutes (Good for 4-6 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook60_good24">Cooking time: 60 minutes (Good for 2-4 persons)</string>
    <string name="sub_cook60_good46">Cooking time: 60 minutes (Good for 4-6 persons)</string>
    <string name="bl_sinigang">
        \u2022 1kg Pork Belly Cuts \n
        \u2022 1 Bunch Spinach (Kang-Kong) \n
        \u2022 1 Bunch String beans (Sitaw) \n
        \u2022 2 Pieces Tomato (Kamatis) \n
        \u2022 Taro (Gabi) \n
        \u2022 Radish (Labanos) \n
        \u2022 Banana Chili peppers (Siling Haba) \n
        \u2022 Onion \n
        \u2022 1 Sinigang mix \n
        \u2022 3Tb Fish sauce \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_sinigang">
        1.	Heat the pot and put-in the cooking oil \n
        2.	Sauté the onion until its layers separate from each other \n
        3.	Add the pork belly and cook until outer part turns light brown \n
        4.	Put-in the fish sauce and mix with the ingredients \n
        5.	Pour the water and bring to a boil \n
        6.	Add the taro and tomatoes then simmer for 40 minutes or until pork is tender \n
        7.	Put-in the sinigang mix and chili \n
        8.	Add the string beans (and other vegetables if there are any) and simmer for 5 to 8 minutes \n
        9.	Put-in the spinach, turn off the heat, and cover the pot. Let the spinach cook using the remaining heat in the pot. \n
        10.	Serve hot. Share and enjoy! \n \n

        Reference: https://panlasangpinoy.com/pork-sinigang-na-baboy-recipe/

    </string>
    <string name="bok_choy_adobo">Bok Choy Adobo</string>
    <string name="bl_bok_choy_adobo">
        \u2022 1 lb. bok choy chopped    \n
        \u2022 1 head garlic crushed       \n
        \u2022 3 tablespoons soy sauce            \n
        \u2022 2 tablespoons white vinegar         \n
        \u2022 1/2 teaspoon granulated white sugar      \n
        \u2022 3 pieces dried bay leaves             \n
        \u2022 salt and pepper to taste               \n
        \u2022 2 tablespoons cooking oil             \n
</string>
    <string name="ins_bok_choy_adobo">
        1.	Heat the cooking oil in a frying pan.                                                                                             \n
        2.	Once the oil becomes hot, put-in the crushed garlic and dried bay leaves. Cook until the garlic turns light to medium brown.      \n
        3.	Remove half of the garlic and then set them aside.                                                                                \n
        4.	Add the chopped bok choy. Stir and cook for 3 minutes.                                                                            \n
        5.	Pour-in the soy sauce and vinagar. Let boil. Stir, cover, and simmer for 5 to 8 minutes.                                          \n
        6.	Add salt (if needed), pepper, and sugar.Stir and then cook for another minute more.                                               \n
        7.	Tranfer to a serving plate. Top with fried garlic.                                                                                \n
        8.	Serve. Share and enjoy! \n \n
        Reference: https://panlasangpinoy.com/bok-choy-adobo-pechay-recipe/#wprm-recipe-container-49523
    </string>
    <string name="adobo_steak">Adobo Steak</string>
    <string name="bl_adobo_steak">
        \u2022 1 1/2 lbs beef tenderloin             \n
        \u2022 1/3 cup soy sauce                     \n
        \u2022 4 tablespoons red wine vinegar        \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup water                         \n
        \u2022 2 tablespoons honey                   \n
        \u2022 1 green bell pepper sliced lengthwise \n
        \u2022 1 medium onion sliced                 \n
        \u2022 4 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil  \n
        \u2022 salt and pepper to taste              \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_adobo_steak">
        1.	Heat a cooking pot then pour-in 2 tablespoons of olive oil.                                                                 \n
        2.	Put-in the beef and cook for 1 to 2 minutes.                                                                                \n
        3.	Pour-in soy sauce and water then allow to boil. Simmer for 15 to 20 minutes. Note: Add more water if the mixture dries-up.  \n
        4.	Put-in the honey and red wine vinegar and allow to boil. Stir and simmer for 10 minutes. Turn-off heat and set aside.       \n
        5.	Heat a wok and pour-in remaining olive oil.                                                                                 \n
        6.	Put-in bell pepper and onion then cook for 3 minutes.                                                                       \n
        7.	Add the cooked beef tenderloin, salt, and pepper then stir. Cook for a minute more.                                         \n
        8.	Transfer to a serving plate then serve. Share and enjoy! \n\n
        Reference: https://panlasangpinoy.com/how-to-cook-adobo-steak/#wprm-recipe-container-50212
    </string>
    <string name="crispy_shrimp_adobo">Crispy Shrimp Adobo</string>
    <string name="bl_crispy_shrimp_adobo">
        \u2022 1 lb. shrimp with head intact    \n
        \u2022 1/4 cup white wine vinegar       \n
        \u2022 2 teaspoons minced garlic        \n
        \u2022 2 tablespoons dry sherry or rum  \n
        \u2022 1/4 cup low sodium soy sauce     \n
        \u2022 1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup cornstarch               \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup all-purpose flour        \n
        \u2022 1 cup cooking oil                \n
        \u2022 5 pieces dried bay leaves        \n
        \u2022 1/2 tablespoon whole peppercorn  \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_crispy_shrimp_adobo">
        1.	Combine vinegar, rum, minced garlic, and soy sauce, and ground black pepper in a large bowl. Mix well.                                   \n
        2.	Combine AP flour and cornstarch. Mix well and then set aside.                                                                            \n
        3.	Put the shrimp in the same bowl. Marinade for at least 30 minutes.                                                                       \n
        4.	Heat the cooking oil in a deep cooking pot.                                                                                              \n
        5.	Add the dried bay leaves and whole peppercorn in the hot oil.                                                                            \n
        6.	Remove the shrimp from the marinade and then dredge in the flour and cornstarch mixture.                                                 \n
        7.	Deep fry the shrimp for about 5 to 7 minutes or until the texture becomes crisp.                                                         \n
        8.	Arrange in a serving plate lined with paper towels to absorb excess oil.                                                                 \n
        9.	Serve with adobo dipping sauce (which is 2 parts vinegar and 1 part soy sauce with whole peppercorn and minced garlic). Share and enjoy! \n \n
        Reference: https://panlasangpinoy.com/crispy-shrimp-adobo-recipe/#wprm-recipe-container-49878
    </string>
    <string name="kare_kare">Kare-Kare</string>
    <string name="bl_kare_kare">
        \u2022 1kg oxtail cut in 2 inch slices you an also use tripe or beef slices \n
        \u2022 1 piece small banana flower bud sliced                               \n
        \u2022 1 bundle pechay or bok choy                                          \n
        \u2022 1 bundle string beans cut into 2 inch slices                         \n
        \u2022 4 pieces eggplants sliced                                            \n
        \u2022 150 g ground peanuts                                                 \n
        \u2022 130 g peanut butter                                                  \n
        \u2022 62.5 g shrimp paste                                                  \n
        \u2022 963.89 g water about 1 Liter                                         \n
        \u2022 118.29 g annatto seeds soaked in a cup of water                      \n
        \u2022 92.5 g toasted ground rice                                           \n
        \u2022 1 tbsp garlic minced                                                 \n
        \u2022 1 piece onion chopped                                                \n
        \u2022 salt and pepper                                                      \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_kare_kare">
        1.	In a large pot, bring the water to a boil                                                                                                        \n
        2.	Put in the oxtail followed by the onions and simmer for 2.5 to 3 hrs or until tender (35 minutes if using a pressure cooker)                     \n
        3.	Once the meat is tender, add the ground peanuts, peanut butter, and coloring (water from the annatto seed mixture) and simmer for 5 to 7 minutes \n
        4.	Add the toasted ground rice and simmer for 5 minutes                                                                                             \n
        5.	On a separate pan, saute the garlic then add the banana flower, eggplant, and string beans and cook for 5 minutes                                \n
        6.	Transfer the cooked vegetables to the large pot (where the rest of the ingredients are)                                                          \n
        7.	Add salt and pepper to taste                                                                                                                     \n
        8.	Serve hot with shrimp paste. Enjoy!                                                                                                              \n \n
        Reference: https://www.hungryhuy.com/kare-kare/
    </string>
    <string name="bl_pork_sisig">
        \u2022 ½ kilo Pork Face ( boiled and grilled) \n
        \u2022 1 pc red chili (labuyo)                \n
        \u2022 1 pc green chili                       \n
        \u2022 2 pcs calamansi                        \n
        \u2022 1 tbsp mayonnaise                      \n
        \u2022 1 pc red onion ( dice)                 \n
        \u2022 1 small white onion                    \n
        \u2022 1 tbsp margarine or butter             \n
        \u2022 2 tbsp knorr seasoning liquid          \n
        \u2022 1 pc egg                               \n
        \u2022 1 pc red bell pepper ( optional)       \n
        \u2022 Water for boiling                      \n
        \u2022 Charcoal for grilling                  \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_pork_sisig">
        1.	Boiled the pork with salt, pepper and garlic until soft.                                                                       \n
        2.	After boiling , grilled it and cut into small dice.                                                                            \n
        3.	Heat the sizzling plate , add butter and saute the red bell pepper, white onion until the fragrances of bell pepper comes out. \n
        4.	Add the grilled diced pork and turn the heat into low.                                                                         \n
        5.	Season with knorr seasoning and add the chillies, top with red onion and egg.                                                  \n
        6.	Garnish with mayonnaise and calamansi.                                                                                         \n
        7.	Serve and Enjoy!                                                                                                               \n \n
    </string>
    <string name="sisig_bangus">Sisig Bangus</string>
    <string name="bl_sisig_bangus">
        \u2022 1 large bangus (milkfish), about 2 to 3 cups fish meat \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup red onion, peeled and diced                    \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup red pepper, seeded and diced                   \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup green pepper, seeded and diced                 \n
        \u2022 juice from 2 lemons (about 2 to 3 tbsps)               \n
        \u2022 2 to 3 thai peppers, minced                            \n
        \u2022 frying oil                                             \n
        \u2022 salt and pepper to taste                               \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_sisig_bangus">
        1.	In a pan, heat oil.                                                              \n
        2.	Slide in fish and fry until crisp and golden brown.                              \n
        3.	Remove from pan and drain excess oil on paper towels.                            \n
        4.	When cool to touch, flake fish to small pieces, discarding bones, head and tail. \n
        5.	In a bowl, combine fish meat, onions and peppers.                                \n
        6.	Season with salt and pepper.                                                     \n
        7.	Toss with lemon juice.                                                           \n \n
        Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/fish-sisig/
    </string>
    <string name="sisig_kapampangan">Sisig Kapampangan</string>
    <string name="bl_sisig_kapampangan">
        \u2022 1 ½ kg pork head (ear, face, tongue and cheek) \n
        \u2022 ¼ cup liver, broiled and cubed                 \n
        \u2022 1 T minced garlic                              \n
        \u2022 1 pc chopped onion                             \n
        \u2022 2 pcs bay leaves                               \n
        \u2022 ½ cup vinegar                                  \n
        \u2022 1 T chopped red bell pepper                    \n
        \u2022 ½ T freshly ground black pepper                \n
        \u2022 1 cup beef or pork stock                       \n
        \u2022 2 pcs calamansi                                \n
        \u2022 3 pcs siling labuyo, chopped finely            \n
        \u2022 Salt or fish sauce                             \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_sisig_kapampangan">
        1.	Grill the pork (ear, tongue, cheeks and face), while removing remaining facial hair \n
        2.	Boil the pork’s head after grilling until it is tender                              \n
        3.	Debone and chop finely                                                              \n
        4.	Sauté garlic, onion and bell pepper                                                 \n
        5.	Add chopped pork and liver                                                          \n
        6.	Season with vinegar, salt and pepper                                                \n
        7.	Pour stock and bay leaves                                                           \n
        8.	Let it boil, then let it simmer until sauce thickens                                \n
        9.	Season to taste                                                                     \n \n
        Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/sisig-kapampangan-recipe/              \n
    </string>
    <string name="laing">Laing</string>
    <string name="bl_laing">
        \u2022 4 ounces taro leaves dried                                                   \n
        \u2022 1/2 lb. pork cut into thin strips                                            \n
        \u2022 1/2 lb. shrimp with head (optional)                                          \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup shrimp paste                                                         \n
        \u2022 1 onion chopped                                                              \n
        \u2022 6 Thai chili pepper                                                          \n
        \u2022 1/4 cup ginger cut into strips                                               \n
        \u2022 1 tbsp garlic minced                                                         \n
        \u2022 4 cups coconut milk                                                          \n
        \u2022 fish sauce and ground black pepper to taste                                  \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_laing">
        1.	In a large pan, pour-in the coconut milk and bring to a boil                              \n
        2.	Add the garlic, onion, and ginger. Cook for 10 minutes                                    \n
        3.	Add the pork meat and shrimp paste and stir continuously                                  \n
        4.	Put in the Thai chili and simmer for another 10 minutes                                   \n
        5.	Add the fish sauce and dried Taro leaves and simmer for 40 to 60. Add water if needed.    \n
        6.	Put the shrimps in and cook for 5 minutes. Season with ground black pepper.               \n
        7.	Serve hot. Enjoy                                                                        \n  \n
        Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/laing-recipe/                    \n
    </string>
    <string name="pork_adobo1">Pork Adobo</string>
    <string name="bl_pork_adobo1">
        \u2022 2 lbs pork belly                                                             \n
        \u2022 2 tablespoons garlic                                                         \n
        \u2022 5 dried bay leaves                                                           \n
        \u2022 4 tablespoons vinegar                                                        \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup soy sauce                                                            \n
        \u2022 1 tablespoon peppercorn                                                      \n
        \u2022 2 cups water                                                                 \n
        \u2022 Salt to taste                                                                \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_pork_adobo1">
    1.	Combine the pork belly, soy sauce, and garlic then marinade for at least 1 hour                                                   \n
    2.	Heat the pot and put-in the marinated pork belly then cook for a few minutes                                                      \n
    3.	Pour remaining marinade including garlic.                                                                                         \n
    4.  Add water, whole pepper corn, and dried bay leaves then bring to a boil. Simmer for 40 minutes to 1 hour if needed.               \n
    6.	Put-in the vinegar and simmer for 12 to 15 minutes                                                                                \n
    7.	Add salt to taste                                                                                                                \n \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/pork-adobo-recipe/                                                            \n
    </string>
    <string name="sinigang_bangus">Sinigang Bangus</string>
    <string name="bl_sinigang_bangus">
        \u2022 2 lbs. bangus milkfish, cleaned and sliced                                         \n
        \u2022 1 40g pack Knorr Sinigang sa Sampaloc Mix (Original)                               \n
        \u2022 1 bunch fresh kangkong leaves                                                      \n
        \u2022 12 pieces sitaw snake beans, cut into 2 inch pieces                                \n
        \u2022 6 to 8 pieces okra                                                                 \n
        \u2022 2 pieces long green pepper siling pansigang                                        \n
        \u2022 1 medium tomato wedged                                                             \n
        \u2022 1 medium yellow onion wedged                                                       \n
        \u2022 2 ½ tablespoons fish sauce                                                         \n
        \u2022 ¼ teaspoon ground black pepper                                                     \n
        \u2022 2 quarts water                                                                     \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_sinigang_bangus">
    1.	Heat a cooking pot. Pour water into it. Add tomato and anion. Let boil.                                            \n
    2.	Add bangus. Cover and cook in medium heat between 8 to 12 minutes.                                                 \n
    3.	Add Knorr Sinigang sa Sampaloc Mix. Stir. Cook for 2 minutes.                                                      \n
    4.  Put the long green pepper into the pot. Add snake beans and okra. Stir. Cover and cook for 5 to 7 minutes.         \n
    6.	Add fish sauce and ground black pepper. Stir.                                                                      \n
    7.	Put the kangkong leaves into the pot. Cover the pot and turn the heat off. Let it stay for 5 minutes.             \n \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/bangus-sinigang-recipe/                                             \n
    </string>
    <string name="bicol_express">Bicol Express</string>
    <string name="bl_bicol_express">
        \u2022 2 lbs. pork belly sliced into strips                                     \n
        \u2022 2 cups coconut milk                                                      \n
        \u2022 2 cups coconut cream                                                     \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup shrimp paste bagoong alamang                                     \n
        \u2022 4 cloves garlic crushed                                                  \n
        \u2022 6 pieces Thai chili pepper chopped                                       \n
        \u2022 1 thumb ginger minced                                                    \n
        \u2022 1 piece onion chopped                                                    \n
        \u2022 1 pieces Serrano pepper sliced                                           \n
        \u2022 1 cup water optional                                                     \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_bicol_express">                                                                                                            \n
    1.  Combine ginger, garlic, onion, Thai chili pepper, pork, and coconut milk in a pan. Mix well.                                             \n
    2.	Add half of the bagoong and pour around 1 cup of coconut cream and a cup of water.Cook until the sauce reduces to a quarter              \n
    3.	Add the remaining coconut cream and bagoong alamang (as needed). Also add the Serrano peppers.                                           \n
    4.  Transfer to a serving plate and serve with warm rice.                                                                                   \n \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/bicol-express-recipe/                                                                   \n
    </string>

    <string name="pork_giniling">Pork Giniling</string>
    <string name="bl_pork_giniling">
        \u2022 1 1/2 lb ground pork                                                            \n
        \u2022 1 1/2 cups potatoes diced                                                       \n
        \u2022 1 cup carrots diced                                                             \n
        \u2022 8 ounces tomato sauce                                                           \n
        \u2022 6 cloves garlic crushed                                                         \n
        \u2022 1 medium-sized onion minced                                                     \n
        \u2022 1 teaspoon granulated sugar                                                     \n
        \u2022 1 piece beef or pork cube                                                       \n
        \u2022 4 boiled eggs shelled (optional)                                                \n
        \u2022 Salt and pepper to taste                                                        \n
        \u2022 3 tablespoons cooking oil                                                       \n
         \u2022 1 cup water                                                                    \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_pork_giniling">
    1.	Heat a cooking pot and pour-in the cooking oil.                                                                                           \n
    2.	When the oil is hot enough, put-in the garlic and sauté until the color turns light brown.                                                \n
    3.	Add the onions and sauté until the texture becomes soft. Put-in the ground pork and cook for 5 minutes.                                   \n
    4.  Add the beef or pork cube, tomato sauce, and water and let boil. Simmer for 20 minutes.                                                   \n
    6.	Put the carrots and potatoes in then stir until every ingredient is properly distributed. Simmer for 10 to 12 minutes.                    \n
    7.	Add salt, ground black pepper, and sugar then stir. Put in the boiled eggs and turn off the heat.                                        \n \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/sisig-kapampangan-recipe/                                                                    \n
    </string>

    <string name="pork_menudo">Pork Menudo</string>
    <string name="bl_pork_menudo">
        \u2022 2 lbs. pork                                                                       \n
        \u2022 1 cup potatoes diced                                                              \n
        \u2022 1/4 lb. pig liver                                                                 \n
        \u2022 1 piece carrot cubed                                                              \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup soy sauce                                                                 \n
        \u2022 1 piece onion chopped                                                             \n
        \u2022 3 cloves garlic minced                                                            \n
        \u2022 3/4 cup tomato sauce                                                              \n
        \u2022 Salt and pepper to taste                                                          \n
        \u2022 2 to 3 pieces dried bay leaves                                                    \n
         \u2022 1 cup water                                                                      \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_pork_menudo">
    1.	Combine pork, soysauce, and lemon in a bowl. Marinate for at least 1 hour.                                                                                        \n
    2.	Heat oil in a pan. Saute garlic and onion. Add the marinated pork. Cook for 5 to 7 minutes.                                                                       \n
    3.	Pour in tomato sauce and water and then add the bay leaves.Let boil and simmer for 30 minutes to an hour depending on the toughness of the pork.                  \n
    4.  Add-in the liver and hot dogs.Cook for 5 minutes.                                                                                                                 \n
    6.  Put-in potatoes, carrots, sugar,salt, and pepper. Stir and cook for 8 to 12 minutes.                                                                              \n
    7.	Serve. Share and enjoy!                                                                                                                                         \n  \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/pork-menudo-recipe/                                                                                                  \n
    </string>

    <string name="sinigang_hipon">Sinigang Hipon</string>
    <string name="bl_sinigang_hipon">
        \u2022 1 lb. shrimp cleaned                                                              \n
        \u2022 44 grams Knorr Sinigang sa Sampaloc Mix                                           \n
        \u2022 1 bunch kangkong                                                                  \n
        \u2022 5 pieces okra                                                                     \n
        \u2022 1 piece eggplant                                                                  \n
        \u2022 1 cup daikon radish sliced                                                        \n
        \u2022 1 piece tomato sliced                                                             \n
        \u2022 1 piece onion                                                                     \n
        \u2022 2 quarts water                                                                    \n
        \u2022 Fish sauce and ground black pepper to taste                                       \n
    </string>
    \n
    <string name="ins_sinigang_hipon">
    1.	Boil water in a cooking pot. Add onion, tomato, and radish. Cover and continue to boil for 8 minutes.                      \n
    2.	Add shrimp. Cook for 1 minute.                                                                                             \n
    3.	Add Knorr Sinigang sa Sampaloc Recipe Mix. Stir until it dilutes completely. Cover and cook for 3 minutes.                 \n
    4.  Add long green pepper, snake beans, okra, and eggplant. Stir. Cook for 5 minutes.                                          \n
    6.  Put the kangkong stalks into the pot. Season with fish salt and ground black pepper.                                       \n
    7.	Add kangkong leaves. Cook for 1 minute.                                                                                 \n   \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/sinigang-hipon-recipe/                                                           \n
    </string>

    <string name="pork_bistek">Pork Bistek</string>
    <string name="bl_pork_bistek">
        \u2022 2 lbs. pork                                                                      \n
        \u2022 5 tablespoons soy sauce                                                          \n
        \u2022 2 pieces lime or calamansi                                                       \n
        \u2022 1/2 cup cooking oil                                                              \n
        \u2022 2 pieces onions sliced                                                           \n
        \u2022 1 1/2 cups water                                                                 \n
        \u2022 1/2 teaspoon granulated white sugar                                              \n
        \u2022 Salt and pepper to taste                                                         \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_pork_bistek">
    1.	Combine pork, soy sauce, and lime juice in a large bowl or resealable bag. Marinate for at least 1 hour.                                     \n
    2.	Heat a pan then pour-in cooking oil.                                                                                                         \n
    3.	Pan-fry the marinated pork in medium heat for 3 minutes per side.                                                                            \n
    4.  Remove excess oil. Pour-in the remaining marinade and water and let boil. Simmer for 45 minutes or until the pork is tender.                 \n
    6.  Add-in the sugar, salt, and pepper then stir.                                                                                                \n
    7.	Put-in the onions and cook for 3 minutes more. Turn-off heat and transfer to a serving plate.                                             \n \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/pork-bistek-recipe/                                                                          \n
    </string>

    <string name="chicken_curry">Chicken Curry</string>
    <string name="bl_chicken_curry">
        \u2022 2 lbs. chicken cut into serving pieces
        \u2022 1 tablespoon curry powder
        \u2022 1 piece potato cubed
        \u2022 4 cloves garlic minced
        \u2022 2 stalks celery sliced
        \u2022 1/2 cup all-purpose cream optional
        \u20222 2 pieces long green pepper
        \u2022 Salt and pepper to taste
        \u2022 2 cups coconut milk
        \u2022 1 piece red bell pepper sliced
    </string>
    <string name="ins_chicken_curry">
    1.	Heat oil in a pan. Fry potato for 1 minute per side. Remove from the pan. Set aside.                                                            \n
    2.	Using the remaining oil, saute garlic, onion, celery, and ginger until onion softens.                                                           \n
    3.	Add the chicken pieces. Saute until the outer part of the chicken turns light brown.                                                            \n
    4.  Add 1 tablespoon fish sauce. Continue sautéing for 1 minute.                                                                                    \n
    6.  Pour-in coconut milk and water. Let boil.                                                                                                       \n
    7.	Add curry powder. Stir until the powder is completely diluted. Cover the pot and continue cooking between low to medium heat.                   \n
    8.  Add the red bell pepper and pan fried-potato. Cook for 5 minutes. Transfer to a serving bowl.                                                  \n \n
    Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/chicken-curry-recipe/                                                                             \n
    </string>
    <string name="sisig_tofu">Sisig Tofu</string>
    <string name="bl_sisig_tofu">
        \u2022 6 pcs Tokwa/ Tofu (dice)        \n
        \u2022 1 pc white onion ( dice)        \n
        \u2022 3 cloves garlic (chopped)       \n
        \u2022 ¼ cup mayonnaise                \n
        \u2022 1 small bell pepper(small dice) \n
        \u2022 1 pc chili red                  \n
        \u2022 1 pc chili green                \n
        \u2022 ½ tsp salt                      \n
        \u2022 ½ tsp pepper                    \n
        \u2022 1 tsp sugar                     \n
        \u2022 3 pcs calamansi                 \n
        \u2022 ⅛ cup knorr seasoning           \n
        \u2022 2 tbsp butter                   \n
        \u2022 Oil for frying                  \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_sisig_tofu">
        1.	Prepare and slice all the ingredients and cooking tools.                                                         \n
        2.	Heat the pan with oil and fry the tofu until golden brown. Strained the excess oil                               \n
        3.	After frying, in the same pan remove the oil and add the butter.                                                 \n
        4.	Saute the onion, garlic, and bell pepper then add the chillies and fried tofu.                                   \n
        5.	Seasoned with salt, pepper, sugar, knorr seasoning, calamansi and mayonnaise. Stir it well                       \n
        6.	Served in a Sizzling Plate and Add more mayonnaise if you like, with knorr seasoning, extra chili and calamansi. \n
        7.	Share and enjoy                                                                                                  \n \n
        Reference: https://www.panlasangpinoyrecipes.com/tofu-sisig-recipes/                                                 \n
    </string>
    <string name="bl_tinola">
        \u2022 1 tablespoon cooking oil                                    \n
        \u2022 1 medium onion, chopped                                     \n
        \u2022 2 cloves garlic, minced                                     \n
        \u2022 1 (1 1/2 inch) piece fresh ginger, peeled and thinly sliced \n
        \u2022 1 tablespoon fish sauce                                     \n
        \u2022 3 pounds chicken legs and thighs, rinsed and patted dry     \n
        \u2022 2 (14 ounce) cans chicken broth                             \n
        \u2022 1 chayote squash, peeled and cut into bite-sized pieces     \n
        \u2022 salt and ground black pepper to taste                       \n
        \u2022 1 head bok choy, chopped                                    \n
        \u2022 1 (8 ounce) package fresh spinach, chopped                  \n
    </string>
    <string name="ins_tinola">
        1. Sauté the garlic, onion, and ginger
        2. Put-in the chicken and cook until color turns light brown
        3. Add the fish sauce. Stir. Pour rice washing into the cooking pot. Let boil. Cover the pot and simmer for 45 minutes. Note: add water if needed.
        4. Add green papaya. Cook for 5 minutes
        5. Add the hot pepper leaves or malunggay leaves. Stir and cook for 1 minute.
        6. Season with ground black pepper. Note you can also add fish sauce or salt if needed.
        7. Transfer to a serving bowl. Serve hot. Share and enjoy!
    </string>
    <string name="adobo">Adobo</string>
</resources>